<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>https://mariosanchez.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mariosanchez.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Site</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/site/</guid>
      <description>Goals and Intentions Goals The main aim of this site is to serve as a web development playground where I can practice and document what I learn. I do it by working on the site code and by posting write-ups on my other coding projects.
Intentions There are many ways to achieve a project&amp;rsquo;s goals. I believe that the best one should reflect the values of the creator. Every project needs to start with a declaration of intentions or guiding principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/uses/</guid>
      <description>When Wes Bos, a popular Canadian web developer and teacher, noticed that one of the most popular questions he routinely received from followers was what kind of software and hardware he used, he decided to create a /uses page. As more and more students and followers started doing the same, Wes created the uses.tech site, featuring profiles linking to the /uses pages of his community.
I&amp;rsquo;ve joined the movement and created this /uses page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/changelog/</guid>
      <description>Unreleased  Embed working demo in Ecommerce Site post. Apply breadcrumb navigation to individual posts and projects pages. Add category tags.  Added  May 25, 2020 - Date and short description to all posts and projects pages. May 21, 2020 - Dark theme media query. May 21, 2020 - HTML language attribute. May 19, 2020 - Code syntax highlighting via Hugo&amp;rsquo;s built-in Chroma code highliter. May 13, 2020 - Twitter cards meta information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/now/</guid>
      <description>Since March 12, a few days before the Safe-At-Home order was issued for South Florida, I&amp;rsquo;ve been mostly WFH, riding my bike and making home-cooked meals. It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting, even enjoyable time, considering the serious situation we&amp;rsquo;re still facing with the Coronavirus.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also been busy updating and optimizing this site, cleaning up the content and improving the architecture and layout.
I also been fiddling with old hardware: I converted an old laptop into a Chromebook and revived an old iPod Shuffle that I found lying around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Gallery</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/photos/</guid>
      <description> Places I&amp;#39;ve been. Things that caught my eye. Like Instagram, but without Zuck snooping around &amp;#x263A;. If you want to build a similar gallery for your site here&#39;s how to do it.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/writingwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/writingwell/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing often on this site lately, so I decided to listen to the audio version of On Writing Well: The Classic Guide to Writing Nonfiction by William Zinsser. The book was highly recommended by Derek Sivers. More than a collection of grammatical rules and techniques, On Writing Well is a common sense guide on how to keep your writing concise and engaging. Here are the passages and concepts that resonated with me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Site with Node and Express</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/express/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/express/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  Node and Express
Source Files | Live Demo
Before we go to our example site, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Express:
Express is a web framework usually paired with Node. It is a light weight tool that makes it easy to build dynamic web applications.
Since Express is made with JavaScript, you can install it directly from NPM. Once you install it, you can build your first Express aplication: a simple Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning and Old Laptop into a Chromebook</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/chromebook/</guid>
      <description>If you have an old laptop gathering dust around your house, you may be able to give it a new lease of life by turning it into a blazing fast Chromebook.
A Chromebook is a special kind of laptop that runs on Google&amp;rsquo;s Chromium OS. The secret to Chromebooks being so fast is the minimalist nature of the Chromium OS. It is optimized to do one and only one thing: work seamlessly with the Chrome browser and other Google services like Google Drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Implement a Dark Theme Switch for your Site</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/dark/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  JavaScript
Source Files | Demo
We will implement a dark theme selector for our site that visitors can activate by clicking on an icon. We will discuss what we have to do to the HTML, CSS and JavaScript files that make up our site to make that happen.
The HTML &amp;lt;!--DOCTYPE--&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;script.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://kit.fontawesome.com/3fe16e504a.js&amp;#34; crossorigin=&amp;#34;anonymous&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;stylesheet&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;style.css&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Dark Theme&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;contact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Exchange Mobile Web App</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/fx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/fx/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  JavaScript
Source Files | Demo
We will create a mobile web app that will display the current exchange of a basket of currencies versus the US dollar. Besides the current rate we also want to display the YTD % devaluation (or revaluation) for each of the currencies.
I decided to implement this project because I work in international marketing, and devaluation is always an important variable to follow when analyzing business results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airlines</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/airlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/airlines/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  Python
Source Files
With this simple app we can type the name (or part of the name) of an airline in a form, and upon Submit we get a list of airlines that match our input followed by its IATA symbol. For example, you can type &amp;ldquo;american&amp;rdquo; in the search box:
If you then click Submit; the result will be a list of all the airlines that have &amp;ldquo;american&amp;rdquo; in their name, followed by their IATA symbol in parentheses:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/rich/</guid>
      <description>Read Naval&amp;rsquo;s original post here.
Seek Wealth, Not Money or Status  Wealth is assets that earn while you sleep. The purpose of wealth is freedom; it’s nothing more than that. Money is how we transfer wealth. Money is social credits; it’s the ability to have credits and debits of other people’s time. Having wealth means not having to be any place you don’t want to be, or not having to do anything you don’t want to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Photo Gallery</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/photos/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  JavaScript
I wanted to post a few pictures from my trips and other activities here in the site. Looking around the web for ideas I settled on a simple square format for the pictures, with a subtle frame and a gray transparent rectangle for the description placed at the bottom of the photo:
University of Miami These are the style declarations for the photos:
img.gallery { padding: 4px; border: 1px solid #ccc; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 2%; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Millionaire Next Door</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/mnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/mnd/</guid>
      <description>PAW (prodigious accumulator of wealth) is someone who has achieved high net worth. UAW (under accumulator of wealth) is someone with low or negative net worth. PAWs may have normal or even below average income. UAW may have high income. It&amp;rsquo;s not how much you make: it&amp;rsquo;s how much you keep. PAWs live below their means. PAWs have budgets and stick to them. Majority of PAWs own their own businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Info Dashboards with ReactJS</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/stocksreact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/stocksreact/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  React
Source Files | Live DemoUpdate: As of May 9, 2020, the API I was using to fecth the stock info has gone out of business so the values you will get in the Demo are all null. The functionality of the app, though, remains correct. I will update as soon as I find another free API.
Objective To build a stock info app using React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Circle with JS and CSS</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/progresscircle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/progresscircle/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  JavaScript |  CSS
Source Files | Live DemoI started with progressbar.js by Kimmo Brunfeldt, which does most of the heavy lifting. You can add it your project by including a link near your closing body tag to the CDN repository where progressbar.js resides.
I used Progressbar&amp;rsquo;s circle as the base for my project (you can use other geometrical shapes), which is intended to create an animated score dashboard to display at the end of a quiz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Enable HTTPS For Your Website</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/https/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/https/</guid>
      <description>I recently configured my web server to serve this site over HTTPS. In fact, if you look at the URL in the address bar of your browser, you should see a lock icon to the left of the URL:
Wikipedia explains HTTPS as follows:
 Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) is an extension of the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP). It is used for secure communication over a computer network, and is widely used on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Basic Linux Terminal Commands</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/terminal/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I explained how to install Ubuntu Linux on an empty hard drive. Now that you have Linux in your machine, the next logical step is to learn how to operate the terminal.
To find your terminal click on the Show Applications icon and type the word &amp;ldquo;terminal&amp;rdquo; in the search box. Then, click on the terminal icon, similar to the one below:
Tip: you may want to right-click on the terminal icon and choose &amp;ldquo;Add To Favorites&amp;rdquo;, to pin it to the task bar, since you&amp;rsquo;re going to be using it often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Install Ubuntu Linux on an Empty Hard Drive</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>When the hard drive of my old Toshiba Satellite died suddenly I thought of getting rid of it, but when I learned that you could buy a refurbished hard drive on ebay for very little money (around $35) I ordered one and installed it.
The clean, empty hard drive gave me the perfect excuse to install a Linux operating system, and to configure the old laptop to become the ideal web development environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eCommerce App with Flask and SQLite</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/flaskecomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/flaskecomm/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  Python
Source Files This app was my CS50x final project.
The app loads a gallery of soccer shirts that includes: image, description, price, and a small form to add item to cart. The shirt info is stored in a SQLite database and is displayed using Bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s card class.
The app includes a series of filters implemented using SQLite queries so you can see only shirts that match a certain filter: shirts by region, clubs vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Blog Front End with React</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/micro-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/micro-blog/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  ReactJS
Source Files | Live DemoThis front end project is inspired in a minimal version of Twitter. We use React components and JavaScript ES6 classes, and put into practice the concept of state. It also uses JSX syntax. We use the create-react-app application for all the scaffolding and heavy lifting so that we can focus on the code.
Our app has six components:
 Our main App.js A Greeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving My Site to a Digital Ocean VPS</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/vps/</guid>
      <description>Update: As of May 9, 2020 I am hosting my site in Github Pages.
I just moved my site to a Digital Ocean virtual private server (VPS). I had been wanting to do it for a long time but it seemed complicated, and using Github Pages to host my site was both easy and convenient. In the end, my desire to learn how to operate a VPS won over the convenience of Github, and I decided to take the plunge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Estate Website with Bootstrap</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/rei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/rei/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  HTML |  CSS |  JavaScript
Source Files | Live DemoThe objective was to design a clean, efficient, and fully responsive website for a real estate investments business. It needed to clearly describe what the company did, and include easy to follow call-to-actions throughout the site.
It was made using the Agency template for Bootstrap, a fully functional form by Formspree, and several jQuery plugins for smooth transitions and a carrousel of testimonials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 6s Discipline</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:42:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, the company moved us to a new office. When we walked into our shiny, new cubicles we found a single sheet of paper laid out on top of our recently installed, empty desks describing something called The 6S Discipline.
It was a concise list of 6 bullet points that summarized a process to keep our work stations clean and organized. I later found out that the 6S concept comes from the Lean Manufacturing philosophy, the principles of which can also be applied to an office setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego Is The Enemy</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/ego/</guid>
      <description>Ego Is The Enemy, by Ryan Holiday, came highly recommended by Derek Sivers. It explores how remaining humble and embracing a learning mindset can lead to success. Here are my favorite highlights:
&amp;ldquo;If ego is the voice that tells us we’re better than we really are, we can say ego inhibits true success by preventing a direct and honest connection to the world around us.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;If you start believing in your greatness, it is the death of your creativity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Calculator with HTML, CSS and JS</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/calc/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  HTML |  CSS  JavaScript
Source Files | Live DemoProject involved creating the calculator interface with HTML and CSS and then adding fuctionality through event handlers and callback functions. It works fine, with some improvements yet to be made, like limiting the display to a certain number of digits so that they fit in the calculator window when the number is too large.
You can try it out here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compound Effect</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/compound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/compound/</guid>
      <description>More than just a productivity book, The Compound Effect, by Darren Hardy, deals with the importance of developing good habits. It is easy to read and full of valuable insights and actionable steps.
Here are my most important takeaways:
Massive results take time Whether we are trying to build wealth, lose weight, learn a new language or any other worthwhile pursuit, success only comes after small, consistent actions performed over a long period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Like TED</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/talkliketed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/talkliketed/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I was rehearsing a presentation, and one of my co-workers recorded it on video. What an eye opener! I was terrible&amp;hellip;
After getting some honest feedback and a few tips, and going through the presentation for five or six more times, my delivery got better, to the point that I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have to cringe when I watched it.
As if fate had it, a few days later I was at a Fedex store and saw Talk Like TED, by Carmine Gallo, sitting on the shelves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Aliases in Linux Terminal</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/alias/</guid>
      <description>If you use a Linux-style terminal you may find yourself typing the same commands over and over again. If this is the case, you may wish to use some shorthand that the terminal can understand. You can do that with Aliases.
You start by going to your user directory and opening your .bashrc file. A .bashrc is a shell script that Bash runs whenever it is started interactively. You can put any command in that file that you could type at the command prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Single Page Application with AngularJS</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/project/angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/project/angular/</guid>
      <description>Made with:  Angular
Source Files | Demo
A few weeks ago I came across the concept of SPA, or Single Page Application, and learned that they can be created with Angular.js, a JavaScript library supported by Google.
Most definitions of SPA you can find online are very technical and full of jargon, so perhaps the best way a newbie web developer like me can understand it is with an example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/gcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/gcs/</guid>
      <description>I use Git to keep track of the changes I make to this site. I am not an expert so I won&amp;rsquo;t go into great depths here. The idea of this post is just to summarize for future reference the Git commands I use on a regular basis to keep this site up and running.
Here we go:
Tell Git your usename and email. You only need to do this once:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/stoic/</guid>
      <description>Finally managed to read A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy by William B. Irvine. The book came highly recommended by Derek Sivers, an artist and writer that I respect and identify with due to our almost identical world views.
I had only a vague idea of what stoicism was prior to reading the book, but based on my little knowledge I suspected that I have been practicing, albeit unknowingly, many of the tenets of this philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/ayw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/ayw/</guid>
      <description>Anything You Want by Derek Sivers is a powerful little book offering valuable uncommon sense advice on how to approach business in alignment with your values and beliefs. In about an hour reading time, Derek Sivers candidly tells us everything he learned from founding, operating and selling CD Baby, the business he stumbled upon when he decided to help fellow musicians sell their work on the Internet in the pre-Paypal, pre-iTunes days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My $100 Office</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/100office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/100office/</guid>
      <description>I needed a quiet space at home where I could sit down and tweak the code of my site, and otherwise tinker with some web development tools I want to learn. Since my second bedroom had some empty space and a window with a nice view of the garden, it was the perfect place to try to fit a small workstation.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of money but I still wanted my new writing setup to look good, so my logical first stop was Ikea&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work The System</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/systems/</guid>
      <description>I decided to read Work The System when it was highly recommended by two respected business thinkers that I follow online: Josh Kaufman and Sebastian Marshall. Also, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been very busy lately and a deep understanding of systems, standardization and automation will bring more control, less stress, and more time for value-adding activities like thinking, strategizing, and keeping healthy.
The book didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint, and left me with plenty of actionable steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Unsolicited Money Tips</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/money/</guid>
      <description>In this short post I will try to summarize what I would do to start building wealth if I were just starting out. Your circumstances may be different, so proceed with caution and don&amp;rsquo;t take this as gospel.
Here we go:
First, if your employer offers a 401K plan with a match, I would contribute up to the maximum amount matched. Some companies match your contribution dollar for dollar. Others match 50%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam&#39;s Rules for Building a Business</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/sams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/sams/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, during a trip to Bentonville, Arkansas, I had the chance to visit Walmart’s first store (originally called Walton’s 5-10), and picked up a leaflet containing Sam Walton’s 10 rules for building a successful business. Pearls of wisdom, straight from the man who built the world’s most successful retailer out of nothing. Since I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find a link to it on the Internet, I am transcribing them below (all of them are great, but I especially like #7, #9 and #10):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/post/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/post/rework/</guid>
      <description>Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson is one of the best business books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. The authors take every single piece of business conventional wisdom and shatters them to pieces.
As the books back cover says: ASAP is poison, underdo the competition, meetings are toxic, fire the workaholics, pick a fight, planning is guessing. All counterintuitive advice, but the authors will show you with facts that following their advise can lead to success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/about/</guid>
      <description>This is an about page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>