<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Mario Sanchez Carrion | Personal Site</title>
    <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Mario Sanchez Carrion | Personal Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/rich/</guid>
      <description>This are my favorite highlights of Naval Ravikant&amp;rsquo;s epic post How To Get Rich Without Getting Lucky.
Seek Wealth, Not Money or Status  Wealth is assets that earn while you sleep. The purpose of wealth is freedom; it’s nothing more than that. Money is how we transfer wealth. Money is social credits; it’s the ability to have credits and debits of other people’s time. Having wealth means not having to be any place you don’t want to be, or not having to do anything you don’t want to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Millionaire Next Door</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/mnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/mnd/</guid>
      <description>These are my 11 key takeaways from &amp;ldquo;The Millionaire Next Door&amp;rdquo;, the 1996 classic book by Thomas J. Stanley and William D. Danko:
 PAW (prodigious accumulator of wealth) is someone who has achieved high net worth. UAW (under accumulator of wealth) is someone with low or negative net worth. PAWs may have normal or even below average income. UAW may have high income. It&amp;rsquo;s not how much you make: it&amp;rsquo;s how much you keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego Is The Enemy</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/ego/</guid>
      <description>Ego Is The Enemy, by Ryan Holiday, came highly recommended by Derek Sivers. It explores how remaining humble and embracing a learning mindset can lead to success. Here are my favorite highlights:
&amp;ldquo;If ego is the voice that tells us we’re better than we really are, we can say ego inhibits true success by preventing a direct and honest connection to the world around us.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;If you start believing in your greatness, it is the death of your creativity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compound Effect</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/compound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/compound/</guid>
      <description>More than just a productivity book, The Compound Effect, by Darren Hardy, deals with the importance of developing good habits. It is easy to read and full of valuable insights and actionable steps.
Here are my most important takeaways:
Massive results take time Whether we are trying to build wealth, lose weight, learn a new language or any other worthwhile pursuit, success only comes after small, consistent actions performed over a long period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Like TED</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/talkliketed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/talkliketed/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I was rehearsing a presentation, and one of my co-workers recorded it on video. What an eye opener! I was terrible&amp;hellip;
After getting some honest feedback and a few tips, and going through the presentation for five or six more times, my delivery got better, to the point that I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have to cringe when I watched it.
As if fate had it, a few days later I was at a Fedex store and saw Talk Like Ted, by Carmine Gallo, sitting on the shelves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/stoic/</guid>
      <description>Finally managed to read &amp;ldquo;A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy&amp;rdquo; by William B. Irvine. The book came highly recommended by Derek Sivers, an artist and writer that I respect and identify with due to our almost identical world views.
I had only a vague idea of what stoicism was prior to reading the book, but based on my little knowledge I suspected that I have been practicing, albeit unknowingly, many of the tenets of this philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/eyw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/eyw/</guid>
      <description>Anything You Want by Derek Sivers is a powerful little book offering valuable uncommon sense advice on how to approach business in alignment with your values and beliefs. In about an hour reading time, Derek Sivers candidly tells us everything he learned from founding, operating and selling CD Baby, the business he stumbled upon when he decided to help fellow musicians sell their work on the Internet in the pre-Paypal, pre-iTunes days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work The System</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mariosanchez.org/img/wts.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ground breaking book about the importance of implementing systems in your business and personal life. Well written, entertaining, rooted in a deeply personal story, the book deals not only with the why but also with the how of developing systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mariosanchez.org/note/rework/</guid>
      <description>Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson is one of the best business books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. The authors take every single piece of business conventional wisdom and shatters them to pieces.
As the books back cover says: ASAP is poison, underdo the competition, meetings are toxic, fire the workaholics, pick a fight, planning is guessing. All counterintuitive advice, but the authors will show you with facts that following their advise can lead to success.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>