<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>https://mariosanchez.org/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tech on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariosanchez.org/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coding Practice Month</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/coding1123/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/coding1123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last two weeks I have been focusing on practice projects. I had been spending most of my time in online coding courses, but I noticed that I was forgetting what I learned because I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently completed four practice projects, encompassing Python, JavaScript and SQL. I am summarizing the projects below, and including a link to their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox?tab=repositories&#34;&gt;Github repositories&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quiz-app&#34;&gt;Quiz App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Console app that prompts the user for answers to different questions. It tallies the total correct answers vs. total answers submitted, and displays the final score once the quiz is over. It is implemented with Python object oriented programming.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/python-oop-quiz&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability-calculator&#34;&gt;Probability Calculator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object oriented programming project implemented in Python. It assumes a container with a variable number of different color balls. The program calculates the probability that a set of balls, for example &lt;code&gt;red: 2, blue:5&lt;/code&gt; will be extracted from the total pool of balls after a random number of draws.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/random-balls&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rgb-to-hex-converter&#34;&gt;RGB to Hex Converter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web app that displays the hex value for a provided RGB value. For example, a RGB value of &lt;code&gt;RGB(234,58,100)&lt;/code&gt; will give you a hex value of &lt;code&gt;#EA3A64&lt;/code&gt;.
The app is developed in JavaScript, using different DOM manipulation and event listening functions.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/rgb-to-hex&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-scraping-for-database-analysis&#34;&gt;Web Scraping for Database Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Console app that uses Python&amp;rsquo;s web scraping package &lt;a href=&#34;https://beautiful-soup-4.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/a&gt; to extract information from a soccer database site, and then cleans and formats the data so that in can be imported into a &lt;code&gt;SQLite&lt;/code&gt; database where we can perform analysis by running different queries. It uses Python regular expressions and string manipulation functions to clean up the data.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/bs4-and-sql&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next few days I&amp;rsquo;ll begin exploring some web programming in Python with frameworks like &lt;a href=&#34;https://bottlepy.org/docs/dev/&#34;&gt;Bottle&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://flask.palletsprojects.com/en/3.0.x/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on AI</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I asked &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/&#34;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; to write a 500-word article about the different types of batteries used in power tools. Since I&amp;rsquo;m very familiar with the topic, I was curious to see how ChatGPT would do. In a matter of seconds, ChatGPT generated a surprisingly good article, accurate and very well written (and not one word longer than 500).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was: those poor chaps writing website copy and search engine fodder at Fiverr for 10 dollars a piece better find another line of work. However, the implications of this technology go beyond just low-level copywriters. Highly paid professionals, like computer programmers or doctors, are also in the path of this disruptive technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to imagine a near future in which you can ask an AI to write a program in Python to tell you when to sell a certain stock, or to use an AI trained with the knowledge and experience of every doctor who ever lived to diagnose an illness based on a list of symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this begs the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;if getting answers to common questions is becoming a commodity at near-zero cost, what will become valuable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best answer I&amp;rsquo;ve found comes from &lt;strong&gt;Kevin Kelly&lt;/strong&gt; in his prophetic book &lt;a href=&#34;https://kk.org/books/the-inevitable&#34;&gt;The Inevitable&lt;/a&gt;, written in 2016. &lt;strong&gt;KK&lt;/strong&gt; says: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;When answers are free or easy, what becomes valuable are good questions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. He goes on to define what a good question is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A good question&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is not concerned with a correct answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot be answered immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges existing answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is one you badly want answered once you hear it, but had no inkling you cared before it was asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creates a new territory of thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reframes its own answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is a seed for innovation in science, technology, art, politics and business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is a probe, a what-if scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skirts on the edges of what is known and not known, neither silly nor obvious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot be predicted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generates many other good questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;KK&lt;/strong&gt; concludes, asking good questions will be the sign of an educated mind. It will also be the last job a machine will learn how to do, and ultimately what humans are here for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS: Everything Old is New Again</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/rss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/rss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/posts/vim/&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful old-school text editor.
Today, I want to talk about another old but extremely useful technology: &lt;abbr title=&#34;Really Simple Syndication&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/abbr&gt;, and why it&amp;rsquo;s making a comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS stands for &lt;strong&gt;Really Simple Syndication&lt;/strong&gt;, and many websites still use it to publish updates to their content.
RSS feeds allow users to subscribe to a website&amp;rsquo;s updates and receive notifications when new content is published.
RSS feeds can be accessed using an RSS reader or aggegator, which lets users view and manage all their subscriptions in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popularity of RSS feeds peaked about 15 years ago, and has declined in recent years due to the rise of social media.
Social media feeds work pretty much like RSS feed readers in the sense that users can follow the sites they want, and read all their updates in one place.
An important difference, though, is that social media introduced two features not present in RSS readers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to post comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A proprietary algorithm that heavily influences what you see on your feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two features are partially responsible not only for the rise of social media, but also for the stress fractures that we begin to see today:
since algorithms optimize for the profitability of the platform, and profitability is tied to &amp;ldquo;engagement&amp;rdquo;, they are designed to make you stick around as much as possible (some would say that they are designed to make you addicted to the platform).
They do so by making you angry or by feeding you content that reinforces your biases.
Social media platforms also censor information, sometimes in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thefp.com/p/how-twitter-rigged-the-covid-debate&#34;&gt;collusion&lt;/a&gt; with the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you ponder the state of social media today, it comes as no surprise that more people are deciding to give RSS a try.
RSS offers a much quieter reading experience, allowing you to enjoy content on your own terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-rss-work&#34;&gt;How does RSS work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An RSS feed is basically a text file written in a format called XML (very similar to HTML).
The content management systems that power websites generate this file automatically, and update it every time new content is added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users grab the feed&amp;rsquo;s URL and add it to an RSS reader, a program that regularly crawls the site and displays any new content in an easy-to-read interface similar to a web page (although there are a few text-only RSS readers as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, media sites would prominently display an &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=rss+icon&amp;amp;t=h_&amp;amp;ia=web&#34;&gt;RSS icon&lt;/a&gt; that linked to their feed&amp;rsquo;s URL.
These days, however, it is much more common to find their social media icons instead.
That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that their RSS feed doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, though.
You just have to look harder.
Usually, you can find it by typing an URL such as these in your browser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;somesite.com/feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;somesite.com/feed.xml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;somesite.com/index.xml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find it, it probably looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/img/xml.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image of an XML page&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just for fun, follow this link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/posts/index.xml&#34;&gt;https://mariosanchez.org/posts/index.xml&lt;/a&gt;.
That&amp;rsquo;s the RSS feed for this site.
In fact, try grabbing a few feeds from different sites and you&amp;rsquo;ll be ready for your next step: adding those feeds to an RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rss-readers&#34;&gt;RSS Readers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as RSS readers go you have many options.
Three popular ones are &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt;, but there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/feed_reader&#34;&gt;many others&lt;/a&gt;.
Most of them offer a free tier that you can sign up for if you want to give RSS a try. Just add all the feeds you want to follow,
and the RSS reader will display their updated content in a neatly organized dashboard that you can customize to your liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/img/inoreader.png&#34; alt=&#34;inoreader screen shot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;small date&#34;&gt;Inoreader Screen Shot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.com/guides/tech/what-is-rss-feed&#34;&gt;What is an RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;: A good primer on RSS. ~Business Insider&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/feed_reader&#34;&gt;RSS Reader List&lt;/a&gt;: Comprehensive list of different RSS Readers. ~Indieweb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vice.com/en/article/a3mm4z/the-rise-and-demise-of-rss&#34;&gt;The Rise and Demise of RSS&lt;/a&gt; A detailed account of the history of RSS. ~Vice&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Learning to Use Vim</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is becoming a very complicated place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rush to make everything bigger and better is creating unnecessarily complicated products. Product managers build feature after feature into products (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_creep&#34;&gt;feature creep&lt;/a&gt;) until something that started simple and did something limited extremely well, morphs into a bloated monstrosity that aims to please everybody (or an entirely new user base) leaving the core user base frustrated and yearning for the simplicity of the original product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the following pictures of the dashboard of the Ford Bronco, the first one of the 1975 model, and the second one of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/img/bronco75.png&#34; alt=&#34;picture of 1975 bronco&#34; class=&#34;gallery&#34; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;Dashboard of 1975 Ford Bronco&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/img/bronco22.png&#34; alt=&#34;picture of 2022 bronco&#34; class=&#34;gallery&#34; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;Dashboard of 2022 Ford Bronco&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing these two vehicles have in common is the name, and perhaps some subtle exterior design cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be lying if I said that drivers back in 1975 found more enjoyment in their Bronco than drivers of the 2022 model, which, if the demographics of drivers of similar vehicles is any indication, will mostly be relegated to hauling groceries and picking up the kids from school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ford is now designing with a different user base in mind, and those who appreciated the basic qualities and ruggedness of the early Bronco will have to settle for something different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not here to talk about cars but about &lt;strong&gt;text editors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-use-case-for-a-text-editor&#34;&gt;My Use Case for a Text Editor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a text editor for coding and writing on my website. These two applications don&amp;rsquo;t require any fancy formatting: code can&amp;rsquo;t be written in anything other than a plain text editor, and I write my articles and blog posts in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; (which is a variation of plain text that can easily be converted into fully formatted HTML for publication on the web).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been using &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Visual Studio Code&lt;/strong&gt; (or simply MS VS Code), which is a great text editor, but as any software made by a large corporation it can be bloated and slow. Also, as I hinted in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/posts/reboot/&#34;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt;, I am trying to wean myself away from technology developed by large corporations, and opting instead for open source alternatives. The time was right to give &lt;strong&gt;Vim&lt;/strong&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vim-vs-vs-code&#34;&gt;Vim vs. VS Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; is an old but powerful text editor that comes with your Linux installation. You can access it directly from the command line and toggle back and forth from Vim to the command line and viceversa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vim was developed before the mouse was invented, and before you could have several windows open on your screen at the same time, you have to use different key bindings to navigate and edit your document. In fact, what makes Vim so popular among experienced programmers is that your hands never have to leave the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drawback is that you have to learn the key bindings and alternate between three different &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxhandbook.com/vim-modes/&#34;&gt;modes&lt;/a&gt; (Normal, Visual and Insert). I won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about the specifics of Vim here, since it is outside the scope of this article, but I will link to a few good resources at the bottom of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VS Code&lt;/strong&gt;, on the other hand, is a modern &lt;strong&gt;IDE&lt;/strong&gt; (Integrated Development Environment). Your screen is usually divided in three parts: folders, document and terminal. Since it works as a &lt;strong&gt;GUI&lt;/strong&gt; (Graphical User Interfase) you can use your mouse and a bunch of menu commands to make your life easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/img/vim.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of Vim text editor&#34; width=&#34;640px&#34; class=&#34;gallery&#34; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;Vim Text Editor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mariosanchez.org/img/vscode.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of VS Code text editor&#34; width=&#34;640px&#34; class=&#34;gallery&#34; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;VS Code Text Editor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difference, though, is the amount of &lt;strong&gt;RAM&lt;/strong&gt; they use. If you want to edit a code file, or write an article in plain text, just having VS Code open will consume &lt;strong&gt;343.5MB&lt;/strong&gt; of RAM. On the other hand, Vim will only use &lt;strong&gt;3.8MB&lt;/strong&gt; (both tested in my own computer). This means that VS Code uses &lt;strong&gt;90 times&lt;/strong&gt; (!) more memory than Vim to work on a plain text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-microsoft-word&#34;&gt;What About Microsoft Word?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t use &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Word&lt;/strong&gt; for coding, since it is not a plain text editor. However, it is worth comparing &lt;strong&gt;MS Word vs. Vim&lt;/strong&gt; for my second use case: writing articles and blog posts in plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of RAM you need to keep a copy of MS Word open is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/3FYIeHx&#34;&gt;hotly contested topic&lt;/a&gt;. It seems that it depends on what hardware you are using and what version of MS Word you are running, In any case, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen figures that fluctuate between &lt;strong&gt;250MB&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;several Gigabytes&lt;/strong&gt; (!), totally insane for working with a simple text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use MS Word because you need to format your text, remember that you can always write in Markdown on a simple plain text editor, and then easily transform your files to HTML to publish your articles on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-summary&#34;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still learning Vim and forcing myself to write my posts with it instead of VS Code. Even if the learning curve is steep, I find that by learning two or three new commands every day I am getting much better. I am finally beginning to understand why those experienced coders rave so much about Vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/blog/classic-sysadmin-vim-101-a-beginners-guide-to-vim&#34;&gt;Vim 101: A Beginners Guide To Vim&lt;/a&gt;: By the Linux Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sive.rs/plaintext&#34;&gt;Write Plain Text Files&lt;/a&gt;: By Derek Sivers&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reboot</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/reboot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start blogging again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;social&amp;rdquo; web has become a toxic and unhospitable place. Although I quit Facebook years ago, I was still using Twitter. Even before Elon took over, Twitter was already a wasteland with the nuance and civility of a South American soccer stadium, where the extreme left and the extreme right hurl quips and insults to each other 24 hours a day, while everybody else is ignored. Why would somebody want to spend time in such a place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to bring back the pre-Web 2.0 idea of running our own website: a place where we can share our thoughts without fear of censorship or surveillance, a digital home made of text files that we can take with us wherever we want, mold it to our liking, and let it evolve with us. Let the reboot begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
