<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Booknotes on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Booknotes on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/pom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/pom/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Money, by Morgan Housel, is probably the first book I would read. More than short term tactics, it deals with the mindset we need to develop to acquire wealth.
I have included the most relevant quotes from the book below, although I highly recommend that you read the whole book.
 &amp;ldquo;The premise of this book is that doing well with money has a little to do with how smart you are and a lot to do with how you behave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/writingwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/writingwell/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing often on this site lately, so I decided to listen to the audio version of On Writing Well: The Classic Guide to Writing Nonfiction by William Zinsser. The book was highly recommended by Derek Sivers. More than a collection of grammatical rules and techniques, On Writing Well is a common sense guide on how to keep your writing concise and engaging. Here are the passages and concepts that resonated with me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Millionaire Next Door</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/mnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/mnd/</guid>
      <description>PAW (prodigious accumulator of wealth) is someone who has achieved high net worth. UAW (under accumulator of wealth) is someone with low or negative net worth. PAWs may have normal or even below average income. UAW may have high income. It&amp;rsquo;s not how much you make: it&amp;rsquo;s how much you keep.
  PAWs live below their means.
  PAWs have budgets and stick to them.
  The majority of PAWs own their own businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego Is The Enemy</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/ego/</guid>
      <description>Ego Is The Enemy, by Ryan Holiday, came highly recommended by Derek Sivers. It explores how remaining humble and embracing a learning mindset can lead to success. Here are my favorite highlights:
&amp;ldquo;If ego is the voice that tells us we’re better than we really are, we can say ego inhibits true success by preventing a direct and honest connection to the world around us.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;If you start believing in your greatness, it is the death of your creativity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compound Effect</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/compound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/compound/</guid>
      <description>More than just a productivity book, The Compound Effect, by Darren Hardy, deals with the importance of developing good habits. It is easy to read and full of valuable insights and actionable steps.
Here are my most important takeaways:
Massive results take time Whether we are trying to build wealth, lose weight, learn a new language or any other worthwhile pursuit, success only comes after small, consistent actions performed over a long period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Like TED</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/talkliketed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/talkliketed/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I was rehearsing a presentation, and one of my co-workers recorded it on video. What an eye opener! I was terrible&amp;hellip;
After getting some honest feedback and a few tips, and going through the presentation for five or six more times, my delivery got better, to the point that I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have to cringe when I watched it.
As if fate had it, a few days later I was at a Fedex store and saw Talk Like TED, by Carmine Gallo, sitting on the shelves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/stoic/</guid>
      <description>Finally managed to read A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy by William B. Irvine. The book came highly recommended by Derek Sivers, an artist and writer that I respect and identify with due to our almost identical world views.
I had only a vague idea of what stoicism was prior to reading the book, but based on my little knowledge I suspected that I have been practicing, albeit unknowingly, many of the tenets of this philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/ayw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/ayw/</guid>
      <description>Anything You Want by Derek Sivers is a powerful little book offering valuable uncommon sense advice on how to approach business in alignment with your values and beliefs. In about an hour reading time, Derek Sivers candidly tells us everything he learned from founding, operating and selling CD Baby, the business he stumbled upon when he decided to help fellow musicians sell their work on the Internet in the pre-Paypal, pre-iTunes days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work The System</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/systems/</guid>
      <description>I decided to read Work The System when it was highly recommended by two respected business thinkers that I follow online: Josh Kaufman and Sebastian Marshall. Also, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been very busy lately and a deep understanding of systems, standardization and automation will bring more control, less stress, and more time for value-adding activities like thinking, strategizing, and staying healthy.
The book didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint, and left me with plenty of actionable steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikigai</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/ikigai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/ikigai/</guid>
      <description>Sebastian Marshall put together this book in a week (mostly from blog content) as a dare to an old-school publisher who had offered to publish it but had been dragging the project for months. As a result, some passages may sound repetitive and there are several grammatical and spelling errors, but don&amp;rsquo;t get fooled: there is gold on those pages if you just can see beyond that.
Highlights &amp;ldquo;Walk the center path with other people&amp;rsquo;s objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/booknotes/rework/</guid>
      <description>Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson is one of the best business books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. The authors take every single piece of business conventional wisdom and shatters them to pieces.
As the books back cover says: ASAP is poison, underdo the competition, meetings are toxic, fire the workaholics, pick a fight, planning is guessing. All counterintuitive advice, but the authors will show you with facts that following their advise can lead to success.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>