<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>money on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>https://mariosanchez.org/tags/money/</link>
    <description>Recent content in money on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mariosanchez.org/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/rich/</guid>
      <description>Read Naval&amp;rsquo;s original post here.
Seek Wealth, Not Money or Status  Wealth is assets that earn while you sleep. The purpose of wealth is freedom; it’s nothing more than that. Money is how we transfer wealth. Money is social credits; it’s the ability to have credits and debits of other people’s time. Having wealth means not having to be any place you don’t want to be, or not having to do anything you don’t want to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Unsolicited Money Tips</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/money/</guid>
      <description>In this short post I will try to summarize what I would do to start building wealth if I were just starting out. Your circumstances may be different, so proceed with caution and don&amp;rsquo;t take this as gospel.
Here we go:
First, if your employer offers a 401K plan with a match, I would contribute up to the maximum amount matched. Some companies match your contribution dollar for dollar. Others match 50%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam&#39;s Rules for Building a Business</title>
      <link>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/sams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariosanchez.org/posts/sams/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, during a trip to Bentonville, Arkansas, I had the chance to visit Walmart’s first store (originally called Walton’s 5-10), and picked up a leaflet containing Sam Walton’s 10 rules for building a successful business. Pearls of wisdom, straight from the man who built the world’s most successful retailer out of nothing. Since I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find a link to it on the Internet, I am transcribing them below (all of them are great, but I especially like #7, #9 and #10):</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>